Henry Harley Arnold Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Military File, 1913-1951 (Box 39-226, Reel 39-227)
  - Message File, 1941-1946 (Box 153-164, Reel 153-164)
    - Miscellaneous outgoing (Box 161, Reel 161)
      - Sept. 1943-Apr. 1944, (7 folders)
      - May-June 1944, (2 folders) (Box 162, Reel 162)
    - Moscow, Russia, Aug.-Dec. 1942
    - Personnel
      - Incoming, July-Sept. 1943, (2 folders)
      - Outgoing
        - Dec. 1942-July 1943
        - Aug.-Sept. 1943 (Box 163, Reel 163)
    - Priority
      - Incoming, Dec. 1942-June 1943, (2 folders)
      - Log, Nov. 1942-June 1943, (2 folders)
    - Sextant Conference, Cairo, Egypt-Tehran, Iran, Nov.-Dec. 1943 See also Container 3, same heading and Container 202, same heading
    - Statistics
      - Action copy records, Oct. 1943-Feb. 1944
      - Miscellaneous, June-Nov. 1943 (Box 164, Reel 164)
      - Record of morning pickups, June 1943-Mar. 1944, (2 folders)
    - Stratemeyer, George, Apr.-June 1943, (2 folders)
    - Turkey, Dec. 1942-July 1943, (2 folders)
    - War Department battle reports, Dec. 1941-Jan. 1942
  - Official File, 1932-1946 (Box 165-180, Reel 165-180)
    Correspondence, memoranda, reports, orders, directives, background information, clippings, and printed matter.
    Arranged numerically by jacket number. An index to files 1-287 is in box 165, and one to files 516-540 is in box 178.
    - Index 1-287 (Box 165, Reel 165)
    - Nos. 1-28, (6 folders)
    - Nos. 28A-48, (6 folders) (Box 166, Reel 166)
    - Nos. 49-84, (8 folders) (Box 167, Reel 167)
    - Nos. 85-106, (8 folders) (Box 168, Reel 168)
    - Nos. 107-145, (7 folders) (Box 169, Reel 169)
    - Nos. 146-165, (10 folders) (Box 170, Reel 170)
    - Nos. 166-204, (6 folders) (Box 171, Reel 171)
    - Nos. 205-224, (8 folders) (Box 172, Reel 172)
    - Nos. 225-228, (6 folders) (Box 173, Reel 173)
    - Nos. 229-237, (7 folders) (Box 174, Reel 174)
    - Nos. 238-254, (8 folders) (Box 175, Reel 175)
    - Nos. 255-258, (7 folders) (Box 176, Reel 176)
    - Nos. 259-279, (9 folders) (Box 177, Reel 177)
    - Nos. 280-287, (4 folders) (Box 178, Reel 178)
    - Index 516-540
    - Nos. 516-519, (3 folders)
    - Nos. 520-524, (6 folders) (Box 179, Reel 179)
    - Nos. 525-540, (4 folders) (Box 180, Reel 180)
  - Reports, 1913-1949 (Box 181-195, Reel 181-196)
    General reports, chiefly administrative and congressional, and special reports, including administrative, technical, and intelligence.
    General reports are arranged chronologically. Special reports are arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - General (Box 181, Reel 181)
      - 1913-1932, (6 folders)
      - 1933-1939, (4 folders) (Box 182, Reel 182)
      - 1940-1943, (7 folders) (Box 183, Reel 183)
      - 1943-1945 See also Oversize, (6 folders) (Box 184, Reel 184)
      - 1945, (6 folders) (Box 185, Reel 185)
      - 1946, (5 folders) (Box 186, Reel 186)
      - 1947-1949, (2 folders) (Box 187, Reel 187)
    - Special
      - Air power, 1945, (2 folders); (5 folders); (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 188, Reel 188, Box 189, Reel 189, Box 190, Reel 190)
      - Appropriations, 1940-1941, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 191, Reel 191-192)
      - Atomic bomb, 1945
      - Atomic energy, 1945-1946, undated, (2 folders)
      - Germany's war potential, 1943 (Box 192, Reel 193)
      - Historical studies, 1942-1944, (4 folders)
      - Interrogations, 1946
      - Scientific Advisory Group research, 1945, (5 folders); (1 folder) (Box 193, Reel 194, Box 194, Reel 195, Box 195, Reel 196)
      - Statistics, graph study of army air forces, 1942-1945 See Oversize
      - Utilization of airlines, 1944
  - Subject File, 1917-1950 (Box 196-204, Reel 197-205)
    Correspondence, memoranda, reports, notes, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of individual or organization and topic.
    - Air defense, 1941 (Box 196, Reel 197)
    - Air Force Aid Society, Washington, D.C., 1950
    - Air Force history notes, undated
    - Air mail, 1934, (2 folders)
    - Air service, 1917-1919, (4 folders)
    - Air service command, 1942 (Box 197, Reel 198)
    - Air transport command, 1942-1943
    - Aircraft
      - Allocations, 1941-1943
      - Military, 1942-1943, undated
      - Mobilization, 1942
      - Production, 1938-1945, (3 folders)
    - Alaskan flight, 1934
    - American Veterans Committee, 1946-1948 (Box 198, Reel 199)
    - Appropriations, 1938-1943
    - Arcadia Conferences, Washington, D.C., 1941-1942
    - Argentia Conference, Newfoundland, 1941
    - Army Air Forces
      - Aid Society, 1942-1944
      - Plans, 1942-1944
      - Programs, 1942-1945
    - Army-navy war college, proposed, 1942-1943
    - Army service forces responsibilities, 1944
    - Atomic bomb, 1945
    - Atomic energy, 1945
    - Aviation, early, 1921-1939
    - Bombing, 1942-1943
    - Bombs, 1942-1943
    - Casablanca Conference, Morocco, 1943, (2 folders) (Box 199, Reel 200)
    - China, 1944-1945
    - China-Burma-India theater, 1941-1944
    - Civil air lines, 1942-1945
    - Commanders, 1942-1945
    - Directives, 1942-1943
    - Dowding, Hugh, Sir, dinner, Washington, D.C., 1941
    - Eighth Air Force, 1942-1943
    - Elks in Mexico, 1946-1947
    - Events diaries, 1943-1945
    - German air force, 1941 (Box 200, Reel 201)
    - Gladwyne (frigate), 1944
    - Great Britain, 1941-1943
    - Hawaii, 1941-1942
    - Italy, 1943
    - Japan
      - General, 1942
      - Surrender, 1945
    - Laux, David N., 1944
    - Lend-lease operations, 1941
    - London, England, trip, 1942
    - London Conference, Quebec, Canada, 1942
    - Losey, Robert M., 1940
    - Mail procedures, 1944
    - Maneuvers, 1941
    - Medals and awards, 1943-1950
    - Mediterranean theater, 1943
    - Meyers, Bennett E., 1947
    - Middle East, 1942-1943
    - Movement of infantry replacements, 1944-1945
    - North African operations, 1942-1943 (Box 201, Reel 202)
    - Octagon Conference, Quebec, Canada, 1944
    - Pacific theater, 1944
    - Philippines, 1941
    - Poor Richard Club, Philadelphia, Pa., 1943
    - Quadrant Conference, Quebec, Canada, 1943
    - Quebec conferences, Quebec, Canada, 1943-1945
    - Racial conditions, Freeman Field, Ind., 1945
    - Radar, 1943
    - Russia, 1942-1944, (2 folders)
    - Sextant Conference, Cairo, Egypt-Tehran, Iran, 1943 See also Container 3, same heading and Container 163, same heading (Box 202, Reel 203)
    - Signal Corps Control Board, 1918
    - State Department, undated
    - Strategy, 1941-1943
    - Submarine, 1942-1943
    - Takoradi-Cairo ferry route, 1941
    - Terminal Conference, Berlin, Germany, 1945
    - Trident Conference, Washington, D.C., 1943 (Box 203, Reel 204)
    - Trump Card or Bluff by H. J. Rieckhoff, 1945
    - Tucson Air Base, Ariz., 1944
    - Turkey, 1943
    - Unification of armed forces, 1946
    - United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y., 1928, 1949, (2 folders)
    - War Department decimal file system, 1944-1945 (Box 204, Reel 205)
    - White House conferences, 1941-1942
    - Women air service pilots, 1944
  - Miscellany, 1934-1951 (Box 205-226, Reel 206-227)
    Directives, messages, transcripts of telephone conversations, reports, war communiques, and lists.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
    - Air adjutant general, July 1941-Apr. 1944, (6 folders) (Box 205, Reel 206)
    - Directives, Dec. 1941-May 1942, (7 folders) (Box 206, Reel 207)
    - Listing of army air corps officers, 1937-1940
    - Mail lists
      - Formerly top secret, Apr. 1944-Jan. 1946
      - General (Box 207, Reel 208)
        - Feb. 1941-Dec. 1943, (10 folders)
        - Mar.-June 1944, (5 folders) (Box 208, Reel 209)
        - July-Nov. 1944, (5 folders) (Box 209, Reel 210)
        - Dec. 1944-May 1945, (6 folders) (Box 210, Reel 211)
        - June-Nov. 1945, (6 folders) (Box 211, Reel 212)
        - Dec. 1945-1951, (4 folders) (Box 212, Reel 213)
    - Official
      - 1934-July 1942, (3 folders)
      - Aug. 1942-Jan. 1943, (6 folders) (Box 213, Reel 214)
      - Feb.-Aug. 1943, (6 folders) (Box 214, Reel 215)
      - Aug.-Nov. 1943, (6 folders) (Box 215, Reel 216)
      - Nov. 1943-May 1944, (6 folders) (Box 216, Reel 217)
      - June 1944-Feb. 1945, (7 folders) (Box 217, Reel 218)
      - Mar.-Dec. 1945, (2 folders) (Box 218, Reel 219)
    - Personal file index
    - Personal file
      - Nos. 34-40, 1942-43, (5 folders)
      - No. 42, 1941 (Box 219, Reel 220)
    - Telephone calls received
      - Sept. 1941-Dec. 1942, (3 folders)
      - Jan. 1943-Oct. 1944, (5 folders) (Box 220, Reel 221)
      - Nov. 1944-Feb. 1946, (4 folders) (Box 221, Reel 222)
    - Telephone calls re Shelmire report, July 1942-Mar. 1943
    - Telephone conversation transcripts
      - Sept. 1941-Aug. 1942, (2 folders)
      - 1943-1944, (4 folders) (Box 222, Reel 223)
    - War communiques
      - 1943
        - July
        - Aug.
          - 1-20, (3 folders)
          - 21-31 (Box 223, Reel 224)
        - Sept., (4 folders)
        - Oct.
          - 1-14
          - 15-31, (2 folders) (Box 224, Reel 225)
        - Nov., (3 folders)
        - Dec.
          - 1-17, (2 folders)
          - 18-31, (2 folders) (Box 225, Reel 226)
      - 1944
        - Jan.-Feb., (8 folders)
        - Mar.-Apr., (7 folders) (Box 226, Reel 227)
- Postmilitary File, 1946-1949 (Box 227-234, Reel 228-235)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, background information, printed matter, and other papers documenting Arnold's interests and activities after his retirement.
  - B-36 aircraft, 1949, (6 folders) (Box 227, Reel 228)
  - Bikini Island, atomic testing, 1946
  - Congressional Aviation Policy Committee, 1947-1948, (2 folders)
  - Correspondence (Box 228, Reel 229)
    - Set A, 1946-1949, (4 folders)
    - Set B
      - Index
      - A, (5 folders); (8 folders); (1 folder) (Box 229, Reel 230, Box 230, Reel 231)
      - B, (2 folders)
      - C, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 231, Reel 232)
      - D-H, (7 folders)
      - I-M, (4 folders) (Box 232, Reel 233)
      - N, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 233, Reel 234)
      - O-U, (7 folders)
      - V-W, (4 folders) (Box 234, Reel 235)
  - Office memoranda, 1947-1949
  - Personnel assigned to Arnold, (2 folders)
- Speeches and Writings, 1923-1955 (Box 235-251, Reel 236-253)
  Correspondence, speeches, statements, articles, notes, drafts and proofs of Arnold's memoirs, Global Mission, and related material.
  Arranged into General files organized chronologically and material related to Global Mission organized alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - General (Box 235, Reel 236)
    - 1923-1936, (8 folders)
    - 1937-1943, (7 folders) (Box 236, Reel 237)
    - 1944-1946, (6 folders) (Box 237, Reel 238)
    - 1947-1948, (9 folders) (Box 238, Reel 239)
    - 1948-1949, (8 folders) (Box 239, Reel 240)
    - Undated, (5 folders) (Box 240, Reel 241)
  - Global Mission (Box 241, Reel 242)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1955, (6 folders)
    - Drafts (Box 242, Reel 243)
      - 1948
        - First, (6 folders)
        - Second, (6 folders) (Box 243, Reel 244)
      - 1949
        - Third, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 244, Reel 245)
        - Laidlaw, William R., draft, (4 folders); (9 folders); (7 folders); (2 folders) (Box 245, Reel 246, Box 246, Reel 247, Box 247, Reel 248)
        - Carbon copy, (6 folders); (8 folders) (Box 248, Reel 249-250)
        - Office copy, (8 folders) (Box 249, Reel 251)
        - Corrected draft by William R. Laidlaw, (8 folders); (6 folders) (Box 250, Reel 252, Box 251, Reel 253-254)
    - Notes, 1948
    - Proofs, 1949
- Miscellany, 1903-1963 (Box 252-265, Reel 255-268)
  Correspondence, memoranda, financial papers, biographical information, photographs, personnel records, scrapbooks, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of individual, topic, or type of material. Container 255 shelved as oversize.
  - Address book, undated (Box 252, Reel 255)
  - Adkins, Edna M., 1931-1950 See also Oversize, (6 folders)
  - Biographical material, 1949-1956, (4 folders) (Box 253, Reel 256)
  - Engagements, 1946-1950
  - Financial papers, 1940-1950
  - Funeral, 1950
  - General, 1938-1951, (3 folders) (Box 254, Reel 257)
  - Personnel records of Arnold, 1920-1946, (2 folders)
  - Photographs (Box OV 255, Reel 258)
    - Album, 1908-1919, (2 oversize volumes)
    - General, 1904-1963, (5 folders) (Box 256, Reel 259)
  - Pioneer aviators, 1903-1957, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 257, Reel 260)
  - Printed material
    - 1918-1944, (3 folders)
    - 1945, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 258, Reel 261)
    - 1946
    - 1947, (1 folder) (Box 259, Reel 262)
    - 1948-1963, undated, (5 folders)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 260, Reel 263)
    - 1903-1909, (4 folders)
    - 1911-1912 (Box 261, Reel 264)
    - 1924-1934 (Box 262, Reel 265)
    - 1934 (Box OV 263, Reel 266)
    - 1935-1940 (Box 264, Reel 267)
  - Trips
    - 1939-1943, (3 folders)
    - 1944-1948, (4 folders) (Box 265, Reel 268)
  - World War II
    - Records, 1940-1945
    - Statistics, 1940-1945
- Military Mail Log, 1941-1945 (Box 266)
  Card file describing mail received by Arnold.
  Arranged chronologically by date of receipt and by an alpha-numeric code assigned to each document. Entries for documents that had the highest national security classification are arranged in a separate sequence at the end. This material had been separated from the Military File and was later returned to the collection.
  - “A-B” file, Jun. 1941-Jan. 1945 See Oversize (Box 266)
  - “S” file, 1943-1944 See Oversize
- Jo Chamberlin File, 1941-1989 (Box 266-273)
  Scrapbooks compiled by Jo Chamberlin, containing memoranda, reports, speeches, military papers, printed matter, and other material.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Air Force, 1942-1945, 1980, (1 vol.) (Box 266, Box 267)
  - Army Air Forces, 1941-1949, 1983-1989, undated (Box 268)
    - Vol. 1
    - Vol. 2 (Box 269)
    - Vol. 3 (Box 270)
    - Vol.4 (Box 271)
    - Vol. 5 (Box 272)
  - Reports to the secretary of war, 1943-1945 (Box 273)
- Oversize, 1930-1955 (Box OV 1-OV 9, Reel 269)
  Oversize reports and scrapbooks.
  Organized and described according to the series and folders from which the items were removed. OV 4-OV 9 not filmed.
  - Military File (Box OV 1, Reel 269)
    - Reports
      - General
        - 1943, Rabaul, Papua New Guinea, air assault (Container 184)
        - 1944, Leyte, Philippines, battle of (Container 184) (Box OV 2, Reel 269)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 3, Reel 269)
    - Adkins, Edna M.
      - Scrapbook, 1930-1954 (Container 252)
  - Military File (Box OV 4)
    - Reports
      - Special
        - Statistics, graph study of army air forces, 1942-1945 (Container 195)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 5)
    - Adkins, Edna M.
      - Scrapbook, 1955 (Container 252)
  - Military Mail Log (Box OV 6)
    - "A-B" file
      - June 1941-Sept. 1942 (Container 266)
      - Oct. 1942-Sept. 1943 (Container 266) (Box OV 7)
      - Oct. 1943-Aug. 1944 (Container 266) (Box OV 8)
      - Sept. 1944-Jan. 1945 (Container 266) (Box OV 9)
    - "S" file, 1943-1944 (Container 266) (Box OV 9)
- Classified, 1932-1949 (Box CL 1)
  Classified material.
  Organized and described according to the series and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Military file, circa 1913-1951 (Box CL 1)
    - Decimal
      - 000.7 (Container 61)
      - 000.7 (Container 61)
      - 000.73 (Container 61)
      - 012 (Container 63)
      - 020 (Container 63)
      - 062.2 (Container 64)
      - 211 Liaison (Container 73)
      - 311.1 (Container 75)
      - 311.23 (Container 76)
      - 319.1 (Container 81)
      - 334.8 (Container 97)
      - 337 (Container 98)
      - 350.2 (Container 98)
      - 350.2 Yugoslavia (Container 99)
      - 373 (Container 110)
      - 380.3 (Container 110)
      - 380.3 China (Container 110)
      - 381 Anti-aircraft defense (Container 111)
      - 381 China (Container 111)
      - 383.6 (Container 113)
      - 400 China (Container 115)
      - 400.112 (Container 115)
      - 400.112 Research and Development (Container 117)
      - 413.44 (Container 117)
      - 452.1
        - (Container 120)
        - (Container 123)
        - China (Container 124)
        - France (Container 125)
        - Germany (Container 125)
        - Netherlands (Container 126)
        - Russia (Container 127)
        - South Pacific (Container 127)
        - Sweden (Container 127)
      - 463.7 (Container 132)
      - 470 (Container 132)
      - 470.1 (Container 133)
      - 580 Russia (Container 140)
      - 686
        - Russia (Container 150)
        - Swan Island (Container 150)
      - 705 China (Container 152)
    - Official File
      - 124 (Container 169)
      - 135 (Container 169)
      - 243 (Container 175)
      - 244 (Container 175)
      - 263 (Container 177)
    - Subject File
      - Russia (Container 201)
    - Miscellany
      - Air adjutant general (Container 205)
      - Personal File
        - July-Sept. 1942 (Container 218)
  - Postmilitary file, circa 1946-1949 (Box CL 1)
    - Congressional Aviation Policy Committee (Container 227)
    - Correspondence
      - Slessor, J. C. (Container 233)